Index's perfect memorization isn't a life-threatening condition even if her memories aren't erased in one year periods.
（上条(かみじょう)）
インデックスの完全記憶能力は―
１年周期で記憶を消さなくても―
死につながるようなもんじゃ
なかった
教会は ステイルや神裂(かんざき)に
ウソをついていたってのか
That means The Church lied to Stiyl and Kanzaki?!
Successfully constructed the most effective weapon against the intruder.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
侵入者個人に対して 最も有効な
魔術の組み合わせに成功しました
Now initiating local weapon, "St. George's Sanctuary".
これより 特定魔術
“聖(セント)ジョージの聖域”を発動
Proceeding to destroy intruder.
侵入者を破壊します
～♪
#06 Imagine
Breaker
Right, I forgot to ask one thing...
（上条）
そういや―
ひとつだけ
聞いてなかったっけか？
...the reason why a non-esper like you...
超能力者でもない てめえが―
...can't use magic...
どうして魔術を使えないのかって訳
No way...
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）まさか…
（神裂）なんで あの子が魔術を？
Why can she... use magic...
Isn't it obvious?!
（上条）
決まってんだろうが！
That Index can't use magic... was simply The Church's lie!!
インデックスは
魔術を使えないなんて―
教会が
ウソついてやがっただけだろうが
（上条）
ああ そうだよ
Yeah, that's right!
And the fact Index would die if her memories weren't erased in one year periods is a big fat lie, too!
インデックスは１年置きに―
記憶を消さなきゃ
助からないってのも大ウソだ
Her brain is just filled with The Church's magic!
こいつの頭は 教会の魔術に
圧迫されてただけなんだ
Erase all that and there wouldn't be any need to erase her memories anymore!
そいつを打ち消しちまえば―
もう記憶を消す必要なんか
なくなっちまうんだよ
Think about it!
冷静に考えてみろ
Did you think...
禁書目録なんて残酷な役目を
こいつに背負わせやがった連中が
...those people that forced her to take on the harsh role of being the index of prohibited books...
...would kindly tell lower level members like you the entire truth?!
てめえら下っ端に 心優しく
真実を全部話すとか思ってんのか？
なんなら インデックス本人に
聞いてみりゃいいだろうが
If not, then ask Index personally!
St. George's Sanctuary does not seem to be effective against the intruder.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
聖ジョージの聖域は
侵入者に対して効果が見られません
Switching to other spells and proceeding with the destruction of the intruder.
ほかの術式へ切り替え
侵入者の破壊を継続します
Fortis(フォルティス)931
Fortis931!
I don't need a vague possibility.
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
曖昧な可能性なんて要らない
If her memories are erased, then at least she'll still have her life.
あの子の記憶を消せば
とりあえず命を助けることができる
I'll kill anyone for that.
僕は そのためなら誰でも殺す
いくらでも壊す
I'll destroy whatever is needed.
That was my choice.
そう決めたんだ ずっと前に…
One that I made long ago.
"At least", huh?
“とりあえず”だ？
ふざけやがって
That's wrong; screw that kind of pathetic thinking!
そんなつまんねえことは
どうでもいい
Just answer me one thing, magician!
たったひとつだけ答えろ 魔術師
Don't you want to save Index?!
てめえはインデックスを
助けたくないのかよ？
You guys have been waiting for this, haven't you?!
（上条）
てめえら
ずっと待ってたんだろう？
A method where you don't need to take away Index's memories...
インデックスの
記憶を奪わなくても済む―
A method where you don't need to be Index's enemies...
インデックスの
敵に回らなくても済む―
A method where everyone is smiling and that everyone wants...
そんな誰もが笑って 誰もが望む
最高なハッピーエンドってやつを
...that leads to the best happy ending!!!
You've been waiting all your lives for this, haven't you?!
今まで待ち焦がれてたんだろう？
こんな展開を
For this development?
何のために ここまで
歯を食いしばってきたんだ？
What have you guys been clenching your teeth all this time for?
Didn't you swear you'd save this one girl with your own hands?
てめえの その手で
たったひとりの女の子を―
助けてみせるって
誓ったんじゃねえのかよ？
お前らだって
主人公のほうがいいだろう？
You'd like to be the main characters of the story, too, right?!
Quit being content staying a side character!
脇役なんかで満足してんじゃねえ
Didn't you want to put your lives on the line and protect this one girl?!
命を懸けて―
たったひとりの女の子を
守りてえんじゃないのかよ？
Then, it's not over yet!
だったら それは全然 終わってねえ
始まってすらいねえ
It hasn't even begun!
Quit getting depressed in this kinda long prologue!
ちょっとくらい長いプロローグで
絶望してんじゃねえよ！
You can reach her if you stretch your hand out!
手を伸ばせば届くんだ
Let's get this thing started already, magician!
いいかげんに始めようぜ 魔術師！
Salvare000!
（神裂）
Salvare(サルファーレ)000
What's... this?
（上条）
何だ？ これ
This is... Dragon's Breath!
これは… 竜王の殺息(ドラゴンブレス)！
It's akin to St. George's dragon's attack according to legend.
伝説にある聖ジョージの
ドラゴンの一撃と同義です
If you even come in contact with one feather, you'll be doomed!
それに たった１枚でも
触れてしまえば大変なことに！
Innocentius!
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
魔女狩りの王(イノケンティウス)！
いけ 能力者！
Go, esper!
Warning.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
警告　第６章 第13節
Chapter 6, Verse 13.
Confirmed new enemy soldier.
新たな敵兵を確認　戦闘思考を変更
Changing battle logic.
戦場の検索を開始
Commencing search trace of the battlefield.
完了
Complete.
Prioritizing the destruction of the most problematic enemy, Kamijyo Touma.
現状 最も難易度の高い敵兵
上条当麻(とうま)の破壊を最優先します
Warning.
警告　第22章 第１節
Chapter 22, Verse 1.
Succeeded in reverse engineering of flame spell.
炎の術式の逆算に成功
Confirmed to be a distorted interpretation of Christian doctrines, described by runes.
曲解した十字教のモチーフを
ルーンにより記述したものと判明
Constructing an anti-Christian weapon.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
対十字教用の術式を組み込み中
Moving St. George's Sanctuary to Stage 2.
聖ジョージの聖域を
第２段階へと移行
Eli Eli Lama Sabachthani?
"My God, my God, why have you forsaken me?" (Matthew 27:45-46)
エリ エリ レマ サバクタニ
Innocentius!
魔女狩りの王(イノケンティウス)！
God.
神さま この世界が―
If this world really is functioning through Your system...
あんたの作ったシステムのとおりに
動いてるってんなら―
まずは その幻想をぶち殺す！
...then...
...I'll destroy that illusion first!!!
War... ning...
警告　最終章…
Final Chapter... Verse... 0...
第０…
"Necklace"... suffered fatal destruction...
首輪… 致命的な 破壊…
Regeneration impo-
再生 不可…
（ｶｴﾙ医者）
フゥ… 謎の閃光(せんこう)に―
A mysterious ray of light and one surveillance satellite destroyed...
監視用の衛星が１基
打ち抜かれたって話だし
（ｶｴﾙ医者）
君と あと２人―
You and two others that don't possess any ID came into this city, apparently.
ＩＤを持たない人間が
この町に入り込んでいたらしい
So, you guys don't have anything to do with this?
…ということとは
無関係なのかな？
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
さあ？
I don't know.
ところで その手紙
あの２人から贈られたものだよね？
That letter seems to be from the other two.
…ととと それは君宛てではなく
あの少年宛ての物だと思うけど
Wait, I think that it's not for you, but for that kid.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
いいんだよ
It's all right!
“挨拶はムダなので
省かせてもらうよ”
"Salutations are worthless so let me skip that."
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
まったく
よく やってくれたな この野郎
You've really done it, you bastard.
...was what I wanted to say...
と言いたいところだけど―
...but if I really voiced out my personal emotions, even cutting down all the trees in the world...
その個人的な思いの丈を
ぶつけてしまうと―
世界中の木々を
残らず切り倒しても―
紙が足りなくなるので
やめておくよ
...wouldn't make enough paper for that purpose, so I'll refrain from that.
必要最低限の礼儀として
手伝ってもらった君には―
As the least of courtesy I can show for your assistance in all this,
あの子と それを取り巻く
環境について説明しておく
I'll explain the complete situation concerning you and her.
イギリス清教は あの子を 大至急
連れ戻したがってたけど―
The English Purist Church wished to immediately take her back,
僕たちをダマしていたことの
説明を求めたら―
but when we asked for an explanation for lying to us,
they suddenly decided to maintain the current status quo.
あっさり 現状維持と来やがった
実際には
様子見というのが正しいのかな
I'm pretty sure it's more accurate to say they want to monitor developments.
僕個人としては―
Me, personally, I can't tolerate any second you're around her.
一瞬一秒でも あの子のそばに
君がいることは許せないんだけど
ちなみに これは 別に諦めて―
By the way, this doesn't exactly mean we're giving her to you.
君に あの子を
譲るという意味ではないよ
僕たちは情報を集め
しかるべき装備を整えしだい―
We will collect information and retrieve her once we have gathered proper equipment.
あの子の回収に挑むつもりだ
寝首をかくのは 趣味じゃないので
It's not my style to kill you in your sleep...
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
“首は よく洗って
待っているように”
"...so clean your neck and wait for us."
あっ… ヒャッ！
A rather extreme friend you have there.
なかなか過激なお友達だね
液化爆薬でも
染み込ませてあったのかな？
I wonder if he mixed in some liquid explosives.
あの少年のことなら―
It'd be faster if you'd go see that kid in person.
直接会って確かめたほうが早い
…と言いたいところだけどね
That's what I'd like to say.
まあ 本人の前でショックを
受けるのも失礼だから―
Well, it'd be rude to be shocked when you do see him,
so let me give you a quick and dirty lesson #1.
手っとり早く レッスン１だね
Yes?
（上条）はい
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）あっ…
当麻！　フフッ…
Touma.
（上条）
あの…
Umm...
あなた
病室を間違えていませんか？
Did you come to the wrong room?
（ｶｴﾙ医者）
あれは記憶喪失というより
記憶破壊だね
That's memory destruction, rather than memory loss.
Memory destruction?
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
記憶破壊？
He didn't forget his memories,
（ｶｴﾙ医者）
思い出を忘れたのではなく―
but rather his brain cells were physically destroyed.
物理的に脳細胞ごと破壊されてるね
あれじゃ
思い出すことは まず ないと思うよ
I don't think he'd remember anything to begin with.
まったく… 頭蓋骨を開けて
スタンガンでも突っ込んだのかい？
Geez.
Did they open up his noggin and use a stun gun on him?
（上条）あの…
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）あっ…
Umm...
大丈夫ですか？
なんか君 ものすごく つらそうだ
Are you okay?
You seem to be in great pain.
No.
ううん 大丈夫だよ
I'm okay.
大丈夫に決まってるよ
Of course, I'm okay!
Umm...
（上条）
あの… ひょっとして
俺たちって知り合い？
Do we know each other by any chance?
Touma, don't you remember?
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
当麻 覚えてない？
私たち
学生寮のベランダで会ったんだよ
We first met on the balcony of your student dormitory.
（上条）
俺 学生寮なんかに住んでたの？
I lived in a student dormitory?
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
当麻 覚えてない？
Touma, don't you remember?
My Walking Church got destroyed by your right hand.
当麻の右手で 私の
“歩く教会”が壊れちゃったんだよ
（上条）
歩く教会って なに？
What's... a walking church?
散歩か何かのクラブ？
Some kind of walking club?
Touma, don't you remember?
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
当麻 覚えてない？
You fought against magicians for me.
当麻は私のために
魔術師と戦ってくれたんだよ
当麻って誰の名前？
Whose name is Touma?
当麻 覚えてない？
Touma... don't you remember?
インデックスは…
Index...
Index... loved you, Touma...
当麻のことが大好きだったんだよ
（上条）ごめん
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）えっ？
Sorry, what's index?
（上条）
インデックスって なに？
人の名前じゃないだろうから
俺 犬か猫でも飼ってんの？
I'm sure it's not a person's name...
Did I have a pet dog or cat?
（上条）…な～んつってな
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）えっ？
JUST KIDDING!
引っ掛かった！
You fell for it!
犬猫言われて
なに感極まってんだ？
What are you getting all emotional for being called a dog or cat?
You must be that type.
お前は あれですか？
首輪趣味ですか？
You like collars?
Are you requesting me to do that kind of stuff?
もしかして 俺に
そういうプレー要求してるわけ？
Huh?
あれ？　ンンッ…
えっ？　当麻 脳細胞が吹っ飛んで
全部 忘れたんじゃ…
Touma, weren't your brain cells blown away?
Didn't you forget everything?
なんか忘れてたほうが
良かったみてえな言い方だな おい
You sound as if it'd be better if I did forget everything, yo.
えっ？　だって…
Huh, but...
According to that frog-faced doctor,
あのカエル顔の医者の話じゃ
脳細胞が破壊されてるんだってな
my brain cells got destroyed, right?
だったら 記憶喪失に
なっちまうはずだったってか？
That's why I should've lost my memories, right?
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
“はずだった”？
"Should've"?
See?
だってさ そのダメージってのも
魔術の力なんだろう？
The damage was caused by magic, right?
Then, it's easy.
だったら話は簡単だ
I touched my head with my right hand...
てめえの頭に右手を当てて―
...and directed Imagine Breaker towards myself and voila.
てめえに向かって幻想殺し(イマジンブレイカー)を
ぶち当てちまえば問題ねえ
幻想殺し(イマジンブレイカー)？
Imagine... Breaker?
The name for this.
これのことさ
That's what the doctors called it.
医者が そう呼んでたんだけど
In simple terms, before the damage reached the brain,
要は ダメージが脳に届く前に
その魔術的なダメージを―
I just needed to dispel the magical damage, that's all.
打ち消しちまえば
いいってだけだろう
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
ウッ… ハァ…
And look at you...
それにしたって ふだん さんざん
人を振り回してた お前のことだ
For all the problems you caused to others this time,
you can take a good long look at yourself in the mirror, right?
今回のことで ちったぁ 自分
見直すことができたんじゃねえの？
Huh?
（上条）あ… あれ？
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）ンンッ！
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
フン！
Wow, this is a mess.
（ｶｴﾙ医者）
あらぁ これは ひどいね
I was going to die... really...
（上条）
死ぬ… ホントに死ぬ
けど あれでよかったのかい？
But, was that okay?
君 ホントは
何も覚えてないんだろう？
You really don't remember anything, do you?
I told you word for word what I heard from those two.
確かに あの事件のことは
２人に聞いたままを伝えたけど
俺…
なんだか あの子にだけは―
I... just didn't want that girl to cry...
泣いてほしくないなって
思ったんです
そう思えたんですよ
That's what crossed my mind.
I don't know what this emotion is,
and I'm sure I won't ever remember anything.
これが
どういう感情か分からないし
きっと もう
思い出すこともできないだろうけど
確かに
そう思うことができたんです
But that's what crossed my mind.
案外 俺は
まだ覚えてるのかもしれないですね
Perhaps, I still remember.
Your memories are dead, along with your brain cells.
君の思い出は脳細胞ごと死んでる
脳には
情報は残っていないはずなんだけど
No information remains in your brain, or should, at least.
なら 一体 どこに思い出が
残っているっていうんだい？
Then, where are your memories?
That's easy...
（上条）そりゃ 決まってますよ
（ｶｴﾙ医者）うん？
心に …じゃないですか？
My heart, no?
Two weeks have passed since the interruption of communication with artificial satellite, Orihime-01,
（ｱﾅｳﾝｻｰ）
人工衛星 “おりひめ１号”との
交信が途絶えてから―
既に２週間が経過していますが
依然 通信復旧のメドは
ついておらず―
yet there is still no indication as to when communications will be restored.
It has been decided the board will have immediate discussions concerning future goals.
理事会は今後の対応について
早急に協議し―
決定するとしています
（ｱﾚｲｽﾀｰ）
ステイル＝マグヌス
Stiyl Magnus.
（ｱﾚｲｽﾀｰ）
ここに来た人間は皆―
Every single person that comes here looks at how I am...
私の在り方を観測して
同じ反応をするのだが
...and reacts in the same way.
（ｱﾚｲｽﾀｰ）
機械にできることを―
"There shouldn't be a need to let a human do something machines do," right?
わざわざ
人間がする必要はないだろう？
Yes.
はい アレイスター統括理事長
General Superintendent Aleister.
（ｱﾚｲｽﾀｰ）
君を英国から呼び戻した理由は
既に分かっていると思うが―
I believe you already know the reason for being recalled from England.
The situation has become complicated.
マズイことになった
吸血殺し(ディープブラッド) …ですね？
"Deep Blood", correct?
（ｱﾚｲｽﾀｰ）
いるかどうかも分からない
とある生き物を―
Its existence is uncertain.
A girl possessing the power to kill "a certain organism", whose existence is not even certain, is being imprisoned.
殺す能力を有する少女が
監禁されている
What has complicated matters is that you magicians,
who shouldn't be within this city, have taken part in this.
やっかいなのは 本来―
この町に立ち入ってはならない
魔術師が関わったことだ
Magicians?
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
魔術師が？
魔術師の１人や２人
つぶすのは たやすい
It is rather easy to terminate a magician or two.
問題は そういうところではなく
That is not the problem.
我々 科学側が 魔術師を
倒してしまうという一点に尽きる
The issue is that we, the science side,
will end up defeating the magicians.
Because the science side and the magic side both hold their own exclusive technologies,
科学側と魔術側
お互いに それぞれの
技術を独占しているからこそ―
今の世界のバランスがある
the balance of the world exists.
It is rather obvious what would happen if Academy City, which governs all espers,
仮に 超能力者を統べる学園都市が
魔術師を倒すと言い張れば―
どうなるかは明白だろう？
insists that it has defeated magicians, no?
なるほど
I see.
魔術師の僕が
魔術側の人間をつぶす分には―
If I, a magician, take out someone from the magic side,
no one would have a problem with that.
何の問題もない
…ということですか？
Correct?
（ｱﾚｲｽﾀｰ）
ふむ…
それに 魔術師にとっての―
And I also possess a natural enemy of magicians.
天敵となる ひとつを
私は保有している
幻想殺し(イマジンブレイカー)
Imagine Breaker...
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
けれど
超能力者を使うのはマズイのでは？
But is it not dangerous to be using an esper?
There are no problems.
（ｱﾚｲｽﾀｰ）
問題ない
あれはレベル０ 無能力者だ
He is Level 0.
A "powerless" person.
価値ある情報は何も持っていない
He does not possess any valuable information.
There are no fears that our information would be leaked by him accompanying you.
君と行動を共にしたところで
こちらの情報が漏れるおそれはない
それは あの少年と組め…
という意味ですか？
You're telling me... to partner up with that kid?
あれには そちらの技術を理解し
再現するほどの脳もない
He knows your technology,
but has no intelligence to re-create it.
故に
君たちの情報が漏れることもない
Therefore, you don't have to worry
that your information might be leaked.
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
分かりました
Understood...
But...
ですが 吸血殺し(ディープブラッド)なんてものが―
...does "Deep Blood" really exist?
本当に存在するんですか？
If it really does exist, then that means...
もし 仮に存在するのであれば
それは…
...that the "certain organism" that it needs to kill also exists...
（ｱﾚｲｽﾀｰ）
殺すべき とある生き物が
存在することも証明してしまう
吸血鬼…
Vampires...
（ｱﾚｲｽﾀｰ）
ふむ…
オカルトは 我々ではなく
君たちの領分だと思うのだがね
I believe occult affairs are not
our area of expertise, but yours.
さて…
Well then.
吸血殺し(ディープブラッド)が吸血鬼の存在を
証明したというならば―
If Deep Blood proves the existence of vampires,
then whose existence will the Imagine Breaker prove?
幻想殺し(イマジンブレイカー)は 一体 何を
証明してくれるのだかね
～♪
Next Episode
（上条）
錬金術師―
The Alchemist, Aureolus Izzard's target, the Deep Blood...
アウレオルス＝イザードが狙う
吸血殺し(ディープブラッド)
三沢塾(みさわじゅく)に
捕らえられている それは…
That girl being imprisoned in Misawa cram school is...
えっ？　魔法使い？
Huh, magician?
次回 「三沢塾(かがくすうはい)」
Next time, "Science Worship".
科学と魔術が交差するとき
物語は始まる
When science and magic cross paths,
this epic will begin!